A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Seal Harbor, ME
  - Seal Harbor - Library, 1916-1961 (Box 74, Folder 762)
    Small annual contributions of $15. Special larger gifts for purchase of books, roof repair. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller, George L. Stebbins.
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence, 1924-1928 (Box 74, Folder 763)
    Bar Harbor attorney. Acted for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in purchase of property. Supervised road work in Park and on island. Details on property purchases for National Park plans. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. H. Lynam, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence, 1928-1934 (Box 74, Folder 764)
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence - E.H. Abbot Property, 1927-1928 (Box 74, Folder 765)
    Purchase of property.
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence - Half Moon Lot, 1927-1934 (Box 74, Folder 766)
    Purchase, also Rest House.
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence - Salary Arrangements, 1922-1935 (Box 74, Folder 767)
    Paid $10,000 basis.
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence - Thomas Property, 1928-1929 (Box 74, Folder 768)
  - Seal Harbor - A.H. Lynam Correspondence - A.J. Wurts Lot, 1926-1927 (Box 74, Folder 769)
  - Seal Harbor - Maine Biological Laboratories, 1923-1931 (Box 75, Folder 770)
    Two biological stations on Mt. Dessert. One connected with University of Maine, one an outgrowth of Tufts College. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made contributions to older (Tufts) station, sought a way to combine the two. Combination unsuccessful. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. became principal contributor to laboratory. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, A. C. Bumpus.
  - Seal Harbor - Maine Biological Laboratories - Karst Property, 1928-1936 (Box 75, Folder 771)
    Land purchase for laboratory by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Maine Sea Coast Missionary Society, 1912-1933 (Box 75, Folder 772)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made small annual donations to society from 1908. Society worked among fishermen and their families. Gave $2,000 toward cost of new boat. Eventually increased to $1,000 a year. Stopped without explanation in 1933. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, and Davison Fund contributions. Continued by Martha Baird Rockefeller. Printed reports. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, J. H. Nelson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Maine Sea Coast Missionary Society, 1934-1953 (Box 75, Folder 773)
  - Seal Harbor - Maine Sea Coast Missionary Society, 1954-1961 (Box 75, Folder 774)
  - Seal Harbor - Maine Sea Coast Missionary Society - Annual Reports and Printed Material, 1938-1960 (Box 75, Folder 775)
  - Seal Harbor - Maps, General Correspondence, and Lists, 1929-1957 (Box 75, Folder 776)
  - Seal Harbor - M. McFarland, 1953-1954 (Box 75, Folder 777)
    Disagreement over architect's fees due after death of architect. Widow and son made claim. Compromise settlement. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Marguerite McFarland.
  - Seal Harbor - Milk Committee, 1928-1931 (Box 75, Folder 778)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s cooperation in effort to establish a permanent milk supply for Seal Harbor. Investigations of various farmers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., D. H. McAlpin, Edward K. Dunham, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - Charles Miller - Financial Arangements, 1935-1947 (Box 76, Folder 779)
    Salary changes, terminal pay.
  - Seal Harbor - William Miller, Charles Miller, 1939-1947 (Box 76, Folder 780)
    Father and son. Gardeners at the Eyrie and forestry work on estate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles Miller.
  - Seal Harbor - Charles Miller, 1921-1937 (Box 76, Folder 781)
    Bar Harbor nurseryman. Did forestry work for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. both on estate property and along roads built through island. Miller also planted vines and shrubs throughout island. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Beatrix Farrand, Charles Miller.
  - Seal Harbor - Miller's Charges, 1916-1933 (Box 76, Folder 782)
    Changes in pay. Resignation.
  - Seal Harbor - Miscellaneous, 1910-1930 (Box 77, Folder 783)
    1910 lease of Uplands Cottage. Rockefeller relations with neighbors and town government of Seal Harbor. Property purchases, construction on house. Small contributions on nonrecurring basis. 1914 letter giving reason for Nelson A. Rockefeller's birth in Bar Harbor. Friends in Mt. Desert. Deaths. Comments on beauty of island. Suggestions for industry. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
    File must be reviewed for David Rockefeller material prior to research use.
  - Seal Harbor - Letters from Atlantic Monthly, December 1919-February 1920 (Box 77, Folder 784)
    Exchange between Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and Mrs. Allen on neighborliness.
  - Seal Harbor - Miscellaneous, 1930-1939 (Box 77, Folder 785)
  - Seal Harbor - Professor Joseph Allen, 1917-1935 (Box 77, Folder 786)
    Neighborly relations. This is the family discussed in the Atlantic Monthly Letters of 1919-1920.
  - Seal Harbor - Liquor Store, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 787)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s reaction to opening liquor store in Seal Harbor.
  - Seal Harbor - Mrs. Hanna's House, 1922-1923 (Box 77, Folder 788)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s aid in purchase by Dr. McAlpin.
  - Seal Harbor - Mrs. Walton, 1926-1928 (Box 77, Folder 789)
    Gifts to widow of James Walton.
  - Seal Harbor - Bar Harbor and Union Power Company - Bangor Hydro-Electric Company, 1917-1930 (Box 77, Folder 790)
    Purchase of electric power.
  - Seal Harbor - Villa Rockwood - Mount Desert Island, Seal Harbor, Maine, 1935 (Box 77, Folder 791)
  - Seal Harbor - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 78, Folder 792)
  - Seal Harbor - Miscellaneous, 1946-1958 (Box 78, Folder 793)
  - Seal Harbor - Miscellaneous, 1940-1945 (Box 78, Folder 794)
  - Seal Harbor - Richard W. Hale, 1929-1939 (Box 79, Folder 795)
    Outspoken lawyer. Refused to sell John D. Rockefeller, Jr. the land that he wanted.
  - Seal Harbor - George Korkmazian, 1940-1955 (Box 79, Folder 796)
    House man at Eyrie. Salary.
  - Seal Harbor - Hancock County Health Service, 1926-1931 (Box 79, Folder 797)
    Christmas seals. One $100 contribution.
  - Seal Harbor - Arthur Vignoles, 1924-1940 (Box 79, Folder 798)
    Ran riding stable at Jordan Pond. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. subsidized him.
  - Seal Harbor - Zoning, 1939-1957 (Box 79, Folder 799)
    Struggle to get zoning ordinance in Mt. Desert.
  - Seal Harbor - Ralph Liscomb and Mrs. Margaret L. Coston, 1936-1960 (Box 79, Folder 800)
    Seal Harbor real estate agents. Maps of town residents.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Biological Laboratory - Contributions, 1928-1949 (Box 79, Folder 801)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and David Rockefeller contributions.
    Folder must be reviewed for David Rockefeller material prior to research use.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Biological Laboratory, 1936-1952 (Box 79, Folder 802)
    Requests to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined. David Rockefeller became member. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Biological Laboratory - Pledge, April 25, 1932 (Box 79, Folder 803)
    Special one time gift.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Chamber of Commerce, 1947-1960 (Box 79, Folder 804)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Nelson A. Rockefeller made contributions to Chamber of Commerce for special improvements in town. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    David Rockefeller material removed to Folder 804A.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Chamber of Commerce, 1947-1960 (Box 79, Folder 0804A)
    David Rockefeller made contributions to Chamber of Commerce for special improvements in town. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 805)
    Park officials' reports on fire. Development of reconstruction plans. Rezoning plans for Bar Harbor. Detailed reports on destruction. Discussions over bearing cost of fire damage. Readers' Digest article on fire, July 1948. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to cost and personal efforts to speed work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Newton B. Drury, H. Bartholomew, Sheldon Goldthwait, Robert F. DeRevere.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction, 1949-1961 (Box 80, Folder 806)
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire, October 1947, 1947-1953 (Box 80, Folder 807)
    Reports to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on progress of fire. His appeals to army and navy for assistance. Use of horse roads in fire fighting invaluable, comments on damage. Experiences of residences. Planning recovery work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert F. DeRevere, Horace M. Albright.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Underwriting Bar Harbor Study, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 808)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to cost of town planner.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - Mount Desert Island Friends of Bar Harbor, 1947-1949 (Box 80, Folder 809)
    Organized to solicit contributions for recovery work.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - Mount Desert Fund, Inc., 1947-1949 (Box 80, Folder 810)
    Family contributions to aid families directly.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - Plans for Rebuilding Hotel, 1947-1949 (Box 80, Folder 811)
    Attempts to interest John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in new hotel - unsuccessful.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - John H. Eisinger, 1950-1952 (Box 81, Folder 812)
    Eisinger hired by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to supervise clean up on his lands after fire and to cooperate with park personnel. Salvage of merchantable timber. Costs to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John H. Eisinger, Newton B. Drury, Robert F. DeRevere.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - John H. Eisinger, 1947-1950 (Box 81, Folder 813)
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Fire - Reconstruction - Bar Harbor Entrance Road, 1947-1953 (Box 81, Folder 814)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed funds for purchase of land in Bar Harbor necessary for relocation of roads into park. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Sheldon F. Goldthwait, Newton B. Drury.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Public Health Nursing Service, 1947-1960 (Box 81, Folder 815)
    Annual contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Regional High School Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 82, Folder 816)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financial survey of high school needs of the island. Study of consolidated school possibilities. Proposed regional high school plan voted down in town meetings. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Edward K. Dunham, Charles K. Savage, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Regional High School Committee, 1949 (Box 82, Folder 817)
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Regional High School Committee - Contributions, 1948-1949 (Box 82, Folder 818)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $4,500 toward survey.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island 1957 Regional School Committee (Box 82, Folder 819)
    Second attempt to create regional high school defeated in town meetings. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. provided small sum for preliminary survey work of possible site. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. T. Keppel, Sheldon Goldthwait.
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island 1957 Regional School Committee (Box 82, Folder 0819A)
  - Seal Harbor - Mount Desert Island Regional School Committee - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Pledge, 1957-1959 (Box 82, Folder 820)
    Payments of $1,100 toward survey.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park, 1946-1969 (Box 83, Folder 821)
    Pleasure with park, access to roads, cutting timber. Road planning, purchase of property. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest. Park construction. Changes in park personnel. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George B. Dorr, Horace M. Albright, Harold L. Ickes, H. A. Drum, Newton B. Drury.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Use of Horse Roads - Permits, 1941-1950 (Box 83, Folder 822)
    Restrictions on autos by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Agreement with Park officials.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Authorization to Build Roads, 1915-1942 (Box 83, Folder 823)
    Giving John D. Rockefeller, Jr. the right to build on public lands.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Beavers, 1928-1950 (Box 83, Folder 824)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and park efforts to reduce beaver population on island.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park, 1937-1944 (Box 83, Folder 825)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Samuel M. Fox Acquisition and Offer, 1955-1958 (Box 83, Folder 826)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes anonymously toward purchase of land for park on Long Pond.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park, 1920-1933 (Box 83, Folder 827)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Camps at Eagle Park, 1925-1929 (Box 84, Folder 828)
    Removal of camps as land bought by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Cutting Wood West of Jordan Stream, 1917-1918 (Box 84, Folder 829)
    Protection of timber for appearance.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Jesuits Field at Mount Desert, 1917 (Box 84, Folder 830)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes toward purchase of field. Site of French settlement.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - McIntire Sewer, 1923-1924 (Box 84, Folder 831)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to cost of sewer to keep sewage from Jordan Pond.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Poaching in Park, 1927-1928 (Box 84, Folder 832)
    Legal prosecution of islander caught killing deer in park.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Proposed Transfer from Reservation to Government, 1921-1938 (Box 84, Folder 833)
    Transfer of lands with motor roads.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Western Mountain, 1919-1922 (Box 84, Folder 834)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid for mapping mountain tops after purchase.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Horace M. Albright and Arno B. Cammerer - Correspondence, 1926-1933 (Box 84, Folder 835)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s relation with government officials. Cooperation from park service. Details of transferring land title to the government. Governmental policies expressed by Cammerer and Albright. Location of roads in park. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Horace M. Albright, Arno B. Cammerer.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Grosvenor Atterbury - Payments, 1930-1934 (Box 84, Folder 836)
    Architect fees for work done in national park.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Grosvenor Atterbury - Correspondence Regarding Western Trip, 1929-1930 (Box 84, Folder 837)
    Atterbury made trip through Western North Pacific getting architectural ideas for Mt. Desert.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Concessions, 1932 (Box 84, Folder 838)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interested in types of contracts made with concessionaires in national parks. Collects information. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Jay Downer.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - George B. Dorr, 1921-1924 (Box 85, Folder 839)
    Superintendent of National Park. Worked with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in planning roads on island. Dorr managed cutting of trees on public lands, received John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s permission to travel over private roads to bring it out. Many details on planning the roads. Dorr held land in his name which John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased. Dorr was moving spirit behind first park plans for Mt. Desert Island. Dorr's history of beginning of park. Death. Tributes. Will. Care of his homestead as part of park. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George B. Dorr.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - George B. Dorr, 1934 (Box 85, Folder 840)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Eagle Lake Tea House, 1930-1934 (Box 85, Folder 841)
    Construction of tea house. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attention to details. Water supply for Bar Harbor problems. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Grosvenor Atterbury.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Eagle Lake Tea House - Sanitation Reports and Restrictions, 1930-1932 (Box 85, Folder 842)
    Studies of drainage from tea house to protect Bar Harbor Water Supply.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Eagle Lake Tea House - Dr. Kast Correspondence, 1931 (Box 85, Folder 843)
    Bar Harbor doctor favors Rockefeller plan, supports chlorinating plant for water supply.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Eagle Lake Tea House - Transfer of Land for Site, 1930-1931 (Box 85, Folder 844)
    Between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Public Reservation to provide for tea house.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Gifts of Land for Acadia National Park, 1949 (Box 86, Folder 845)
    Copies of letters of gift of land to government for park and offers to build roads. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Gifts of Land for Acadia National Park, 1919-1933 (Box 86, Folder 846)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - A. H. Lynam, 1920-1923 (Box 86, Folder 847)
    Authority to Lynam to buy land for National Park as Mr. Rockefeller's agent. Also looked after the other Rockefeller interests in relation to park. Primarily land purchases on west side of island. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, A. H. Lynam.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Public Reservation, 1919-1920 (Box 86, Folder 848)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Authorizations and Payments, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 849)
    Summaries.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Beaton, Bingham, and Roberts Lots, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 850)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Brewer Property, 1922-1923 (Box 86, Folder 851)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Property purchased on October 15, 1922 for $1,650.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Capitola L. Bunker Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 852)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Brown Mountain, 1924 (Box 86, Folder 853)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Candage Lot, 1922-1923 (Box 86, Folder 854)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Charles H. Clement Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 855)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Lot totaled 25.6 acres.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Clement Lot B - East Side Jordan Pond, 1922-1927 (Box 86, Folder 856)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Lot totaled 1 acre.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Cunningham Lot, 1924 (Box 86, Folder 857)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Haight Property, 1923-1924 (Box 86, Folder 858)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Hamilton Lots, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 859)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Hamor Lot, 1924 (Box 86, Folder 860)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Mildred Morrison Jones Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 861)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - George N. Jordan Lot, 1922-1923 (Box 86, Folder 862)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - McFarland Properties, 1924-1929 (Box 86, Folder 863)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Properties purchased for $3,000.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - H. L. Martin Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 864)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Lot totaled 23 acres.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - McIntire Property, 1916 (Box 86, Folder 865)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Pendleton-Bates Property, 1921-1922 (Box 86, Folder 866)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Preble Lots, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 867)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Rich Property, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 868)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Snow Lot, 1922-1924 (Box 86, Folder 869)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Stebbins Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 870)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Lot also known as the Fox Lot. Lot totaled 34.25 acres.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Somes Property, 1923-1927 (Box 86, Folder 871)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Property located on Sargent Mountain. Purchased for $4,000.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Stoughton Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 872)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Somes Property, 1923-1924 (Box 86, Folder 873)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Purchased through Mr. Martin. Property located on Long Pond.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Suminsby Lot, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 874)
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Property Purchases - Travelli Lot, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 875)
    Cost of purchase, transfer of title, details of title of land purchased by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift to national park. Lot purchased for $10,000.
  - Seal Harbor - National Park - Road Controversy, 1920 (Box 87, Folder 876)
    Opposition to building of carriage roads through new section of park. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. decides to stop building roads in view of such opposition, even if it is a minority voice. Surge of support for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from many residents of the area. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George Pepper, George B. Dorr.
  - Seal Harbor - Neighborhood Hall Association, 1939-1949 (Box 87, Folder 877)
    Organized to promote social welfare of community. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. a stockholder and contributor to organization. Built hall for motion pictures, dances, meetings. Annual contributions, $100, $300. Also called Seal Harbor Community Hall Association. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave his stock to Nelson A. Rockefeller in 1943. Turned over to Village Corporation in 1950. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Edward K. Dunham, George L. Stebbins, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
  - Seal Harbor - Neighborhood Hall Association - Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Sons, 1936-1949 (Box 87, Folder 878)
    By John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, $25 a year.
  - Seal Harbor - Neighborhood Hall Association - Voting Trust, 1940 (Box 87, Folder 879)